# Daniel Fiuza Dosil, Ph.D.

## **Profile**

#### **Contact:**

Flat B, 20-22, Capital House, Craven Road, W2 3PX, London

#### Mobile no:

+34 644 854 383 +44 7532 735600

#### **Email:**

dafiuzadosil@gmail.com

## Languages:

English, Spanish

## **Programming** Languages:

Matlab, Python C, SQL, LATEX, Bash

#### **Data Science:**

NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy

### **Machine Learning:**

Keras, SKlearn, MLFlow, Optuna, Pycaret

#### Other Tools:

[BI]: Tableau, PowerBI, Airtable, DBeaver, MySQL, PostgreSQL; [Automation]: Zapier. Zoho Flow, Zoho CRM; [Cloud]: AWS (S3, RDS, EC2, Lambda, Elastic Beanstalk, Sagemaker, IoT); [Software]: GitHub, Docker, CSS, HTML, Flask,

#### **Skills:**

Airflow

Analytical and critical thinking, Problem-solving, Business acumen, Effective communicator, Agile Methodology

## **Hobbies:**

Running, Cycling, Swimming, Climbing, Cooking I am Daniel, a highly adaptable data scientist and business intelligence analyst with experience in leading and developing end-to-end data science products. I have excellent analytical, coding, business acumen and problem-solving skills acquired during my educational, research and commercial period. I have developed great communication skills, and I can present complex topics in simple terms. I am very adaptable, creative and resilient.

## **Experience**

2021-Raptor BioTech

Lead Data Scientist

In charge of developing a medical AI solution for disease diagnosis. End-to-end development: the ML solution, data engineering, web application, cloud deployment, monitoring, etc. Was also in charge of managing, interviewing, growing the team, applying for funding and supervising the software engineering development.

London, UK

London, UK

London, UK

London, UK

London, UK

London, UK

Raptor BioTech

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

Aalborg, Denmark

2021-**Bryant Dental** 

Business Intelligence Analyst

Created a unified centralised data source for the company in a real-time relational database. Produced real-time dashboards with KPIs for the business, and implemented ML solutions for sales forecasting, and NLP sentiment analysis. Automation and web applications were created to optimise the operations of the company and advised the stakeholders on data-driven business strategy.

#### 2021-2021 LoveHolidavs

Data Scientist (Fixed-Term Contract)

Developed a holiday recommendation system to increase user engagement and the number of bookings. Applied decision tree ensembles and user clustering to model and increase the probability of a user booking a holiday.

2019-2021 **London South Bank University** 

Associate Lecturer

2016-2021 FluidTech

Co-Founder & Head of Engineering

2017-2021 **First Tutors** 

Private Tutor

2017-2020 **Imperial College London** 

Graduate Teaching Assistant (GTA)

## **Education**

2021-

2021-2021	Fellow in Data Science	Faculty AI
2017-2021	PhD Fluid Mechanics, Civil and Environmental Engineering	Imperial College London
2014-2016	MSc Energy Engineering (Thermal Energy and Process Engineer	ering) Aalborg University
2015-2016	MSc Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering	West Virginia University.

2011-2015 **BSc** Industrial Engineering (Energy Technologies)

**Predicting COVID-19 Infection from Breath Biomarkers** 

## **Data Science Projects**

2020-2021	Structural Damage Detection using LSTM Neural Networks	Freelance
2020-2020	Holiday Recommendation System	LoveHolidays
2017-2020	Development of Computational Tools for Real-time Image Processing	Imperial College London